<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xmlns:eg="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
     xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/"
     xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xml:lang="eng"
     xml:id="elem-appraisal"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>appraisal</gi>
      <seg type="fullName">Appraisal Information</seg>
   </head>
   <div type="summary">
      <p>An element for documenting decisions and actions related to assessing the archival value and disposition of the materials being described.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>appraisal, blockquote, chronlist, head, list, p, table</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>appraisal, archdesc, c, c01, c02, c03, c04, c05, c06, c07, c08, c09, c10, c11, c12</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <table>
         <row>
            <cell>altrender</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>audience</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>encodinganalog</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>id</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>lang</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>localtype</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>script</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
      </table>
   </div>
   <div type="descriptionAndUsage">
      <p>A statement of the rationale for decisions related to appraisal and disposition of the materials being described. Such decisions may be based upon the records' current administrative, legal, and fiscal use; their evidential, intrinsic, and informational value; their arrangement and condition; and their relationship to other records. May include information about destruction actions, sampling, and disposition schedules.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="availability">
      <p>Optional, repeatable</p>
   </div>
   <div type="references">
      <p>ISAD(G) 3.3.2</p>
      <p>MARC 583</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <eg:egXML>
         <ead:appraisal>
            <ead:p>The records of the Mid-Ocean Dynamics Experiment came to the
                           Institute Archives in two accessions in 1980 and 1982. During processing
                           the collection was reduced from fifteen cubic feet to four by discarding
                           duplicate materials, financial records, and publications not authored by
                           MODE participants. Forty charts and six inches of raw data presented the
                           primary appraisal issues. The raw data consisted of bulletins and reports
                           referring to float positions, moorings, isotherms, geostrophic velocity
                           calculations, ships' summaries, and work proposed and work carried out
                           during the MODE-I experiment. As this raw data was recapitulated in
                           weekly <ead:title render="underline">
                  <ead:part>MODE Hot Line Bulletins</ead:part>
               </ead:title>, only a sampling was retained in
                           the collection. Also discarded were ten charts for which there were no
                           descriptions of indicated data points, nor were dates or test site
                           locations provided.</ead:p>
            <ead:p>Six inches of materials pertaining to the POLYMODE project, 1973-1980, were added to the Institute Archives POLYMODE collection.</ead:p>
            <ead:p>The appraisal of this collection was carried out in consultation with Robert Heinmiller, a research associate at Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution during MODE.</ead:p>
         </ead:appraisal>
      </eg:egXML>
      <eg:egXML>
         <ead:appraisal>
            <ead:chronlist>
               <ead:chronitem>
                  <ead:datesingle standarddate="1975">1975</ead:datesingle>
                  <ead:event>Appraisal provided by donor, $12,500.</ead:event>
               </ead:chronitem>
               <ead:chronitem>
                  <ead:datesingle standarddate="2008">2008</ead:datesingle>
                  <ead:event>Appraised for insurance purposes, $15,750.</ead:event>
               </ead:chronitem>
            </ead:chronlist>
         </ead:appraisal>
      </eg:egXML>
   </div>
</div>
