<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xmlns:eg="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
     xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/"
     xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xml:lang="eng"
     xml:id="elem-ptr"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>ptr</gi>
      <seg type="fullName">Pointer</seg>
   </head>
   <div type="summary">
      <p>An empty element that provides links to content that may be internal or external to the finding aid.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>[empty]</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>abstract, addressline, archref, author, bibref, citation, container, date, datesingle, didnote, dimensions, edition, emph, entry, event, fromdate, head, head01, head02, head03, indexentry, item, label, materialspec, num, p, part, physdesc, physfacet, physloc, ptrgrp, publisher, quote, ref, sponsor, subtitle, titleproper, todate, unitdate, unitid, unittitle</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <table>
         <row>
            <cell>actuate</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: none, onload, onrequest, other)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>altrender</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>arcrole</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>audience</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>entityref</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>href</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>id</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>linkrole</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>linktitle</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>show</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: embed, new, none, other, replace)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>target</cell>
            <cell>Optional (IDREF)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>xpointer</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
      </table>
   </div>
   <div type="descriptionAndUsage">
      <p>An empty linking element that provides links both to content within a finding
                     aid, or from a finding aid to external content. <gi>ptr</gi> may be used in a
                     variety of ways in an encoded finding aid. For example, <gi>ptr</gi> may
                     provide an internal link from one location in a finding aid to another. Or,
                        <gi>ptr</gi> might be used to embed an image into the text of a finding aid.
                     Unlike <gi>ref</gi>, <gi>ptr</gi> cannot contain text or child elements to
                     describe the referenced object. When <gi>ptr</gi> is used to embed internal
                     links, the text of the link must be generated by the transforming style
                     sheet.</p>
      <p>Attribute usage:</p>
      <list>
         <item>Use <att>target</att> to link to another element within the finding
                        aid.</item>
         <item>Use <att>href</att> to link to or embed an external file.</item>
         <item>Use <att>linkrole</att> to provide a URI that characterizes the nature of
                        the remote resource to which <gi>ptr</gi> links.</item>
         <item>Use <att>arcrole</att> to provide a URI that characterizes the nature of
                        the link itself.</item>
      </list>
      <p>See also:</p>
      <list>
         <item>
            <gi>ref</gi>, if you wish to encode text and child elements to display a
                        link to the external file.</item>
         <item>
            <gi>dao</gi>, if you wish to link to or embed an external file in
                           <gi>did</gi>.</item>
      </list>
   </div>
   <div type="availability">
      <p>Within <gi>ptrgrp</gi>: One of <gi>ptr</gi> or <gi>ref</gi> is required,
                     repeatable</p>
      <p>Within all other parents: Optional, repeatable</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <eg:egXML>
         <ead:appraisal>
            <ead:p>This collection was re-appraised by repository staff in
                           1992 in order to facilitate use by weeding the collection of materials no
                           longed deemed as having evidential or informational value. A list of
                           materials removed from the collection after the re-appraisal is provided
                           at the end of this guide.<ead:ptr actuate="onrequest" show="replace" target="mss1982-062_add2"/>
            </ead:p>
         </ead:appraisal>
      </eg:egXML>
   </div>
</div>
