<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xmlns:eg="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
     xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/"
     xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xml:lang="eng"
     xml:id="elem-ref"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>ref</gi>
      <seg type="fullName">Reference</seg>
   </head>
   <div type="summary">
      <p>An element that provides a link to content that may be internal or external to the finding aid.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>[text], abbr, corpname, date, emph, expan, famname, footnote, function, genreform, geogname, lb, name, num, occupation, persname, ptr, quote, subject, title</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>abstract, addressline, archref, author, bibref, citation, container, date, datesingle, didnote, dimensions, edition, emph, entry, event, fromdate, head, head01, head02, head03, indexentry, item, label, materialspec, num, p, part, physdesc, physfacet, physloc, ptrgrp, publisher, quote, sponsor, subtitle, titleproper, todate, unitdate, unitid, unittitle</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <table>
         <row>
            <cell>actuate</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: none, onload, onrequest, other)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>altrender</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>arcrole</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>audience</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>entityref</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>href</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>id</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>lang</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>linkrole</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>linktitle</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>script</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>show</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: embed, new, none, other, replace)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>target</cell>
            <cell>Optional (IDREF)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>xpointer</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
      </table>
   </div>
   <div type="descriptionAndUsage">
      <p>
         <gi>ref</gi> may be used in a variety of ways in an encoded finding aid. For
                     example, <gi>ref</gi> may provide an internal link from one <gi>c</gi> to
                     another related <gi>c</gi> in the same way that See and See also references
                     direct readers of paper-based finding aids. Or, <gi>ref</gi> might be used to
                     direct the reader from text in a scope and content note to a description of a
                        <gi>c</gi> in a contents list. <gi>ref</gi> might also point to an external
                     file, for example, a finding aid for a related collection at another
                     repository.</p>
      <p>See also:</p>
      <list>
         <item>Use <gi>ptr</gi> to provide a reference to a file when text or child
                        elements that describe the referenced object are not needed, for example,
                        when providing an image to be embedded in the finding aid.</item>
      </list>
      <p>Attribute usage:</p>
      <list>
         <item>Use <att>target</att> to link to another element within the finding
                        aid.</item>
         <item>Use <att>href</att> to link to or embed an external file.</item>
         <item>Use <att>linkrole</att> to provide a URI that characterizes the nature of
                        the remote resource to which <gi>ref</gi> links.</item>
         <item>Use <att>arcrole</att> to provide a URI that characterizes the nature of
                        the link itself.</item>
      </list>
   </div>
   <div type="availability">
      <p>Within <gi>ptrgrp</gi>: One of <gi>ptr</gi> or <gi>ref</gi> is required,
                     repeatable</p>
      <p>Within all other parents: Optional, repeatable</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <eg:egXML>
         <ead:indexentry>
            <ead:genreform>
               <ead:part>Pedigree, 20th cent.</ead:part>
            </ead:genreform>
            <ead:ref linkrole="internal"
                     target="EngC5769-f74"
                     show="replace"
                     actuate="onrequest">MS. Eng. c. 5769, fol. 74</ead:ref>
         </ead:indexentry>
      </eg:egXML>
   </div>
</div>
