<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xmlns:eg="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
     xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/"
     xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xml:lang="eng"
     xml:id="elem-c"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>c</gi>
      <seg type="fullName"/>
   </head>
   <div type="summary">
      <p>An element that designates a subordinate part of the materials being described.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>accessrestrict, accruals, acqinfo, altformavail, appraisal, arrangement, bibliography, bioghist, c, controlaccess, custodhist, did, fileplan, head, index, legalstatus, odd, originalsloc, otherfindaid, phystech, prefercite, processinfo, relatedmaterial, relations, scopecontent, separatedmaterial, thead, userestrict</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <table>
         <row>
            <cell>altrender</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>audience</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>base</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>encodinganalog</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>id</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>lang</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>level</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: class, collection, file, fonds, item, otherlevel, recordgrp, series, subfonds, subgrp, subseries)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>otherlevel</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>script</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
      </table>
   </div>
   <div type="descriptionAndUsage">
      <p>As a wrapper for a set of elements, <gi>c</gi> provides information about the
                     content, context, and extent of a subordinate body of materials. It is always a
                     child or descendant of <gi>dsc</gi> and often a child and/or parent of another
                        <gi>c</gi>. Each <gi>c</gi> identifies a logical section, or level, of the
                     described materials. The physical filing separations between components need
                     not always coincide with the intellectual separations. For example, a
                        <gi>c</gi> that designates dramatic works might end in the same box in which
                     the next <gi>c</gi> begins with short stories. Also, not every <gi>c</gi>
                     directly corresponds to a folder or other physical entity. Some <gi>c</gi>
                     elements simply represent a logical point in a hierarchical description.</p>
      <p>Components may be subdivided into smaller and smaller components and may
                     eventually reach the level of a single item. For example, the components of a
                     collection may be a series, components of series may be subseries, components
                     of subseries may be files, and components of files may be items. A component
                     may be either an unnumbered <gi>c</gi> or a numbered <gi>c01</gi>,
                     <gi>c02</gi>, etc. Numbered and un-numbered components cannot be mixed in an
                     EAD instance, and only up to twelve numbered <gi>c</gi>s,
                        (<gi>c01</gi>-<gi>c12</gi>) may be used in an EAD instance. Numbering
                     components may assist a finding aid encoder in accurately nesting
                     components.</p>
      <p>Attribute usage:</p>
      <list>
         <item>Use <att>base</att> to specify a base URI other than the URI of the EAD
                        instance for the purpose of resolving any relative URIs contained within
                           <gi>c</gi>.</item>
         <item>Use <att>encodinganalog</att> to indicate corresponding data elements
                        categories in another data format, such as MARC.</item>
         <item>Use <att>level</att> to identify the logical type of the component, using
                        one of these values: class, collection, file, fonds, item, otherlevel,
                        recordgrp, series, subfonds, subgrp, subseries. Assigning <att>level</att>
                        for the highest <gi>c</gi> is recommended; thereafter the attribute may be
                        used when the repository deems it useful, or when encoding protocols dictate
                        its use.</item>
         <item>Use <att>otherlevel</att> to specify the level of a component for which
                        the <att>level</att> has been set to "otherlevel."</item>
      </list>
   </div>
   <div type="availability">
      <p>Optional, repeatable</p>
   </div>
   <div type="references">
      <p>ISAD(G) 3.1.4 is equivalent to <att>level</att>
      </p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <eg:egXML>
         <ead:dsc dsctype="combined">
            <ead:c level="series">
               <ead:did>
                  <ead:unitid>Series 1</ead:unitid>
                  <ead:unittitle>Correspondence</ead:unittitle>
               </ead:did>
               <ead:scopecontent>[...]</ead:scopecontent>
               <ead:c level="subseries">
                  <ead:did>
                     <ead:unitid>Subseries 1.1</ead:unitid>
                     <ead:unittitle>Outgoing Correspondence</ead:unittitle>
                  </ead:did>
                  <ead:c level="file">
                     <ead:did>
                        <ead:unittitle>Abbinger-Aldrich</ead:unittitle>
                     </ead:did>
                  </ead:c> [. . .] </ead:c>
               <ead:c level="subseries">
                  <ead:did>
                     <ead:unitid>Subseries 1.2</ead:unitid>
                     <ead:unittitle>Incoming Correspondence</ead:unittitle>
                  </ead:did>
                  <ead:c level="file">
                     <ead:did>
                        <ead:unittitle>Adams-Ayers</ead:unittitle>
                     </ead:did>
                  </ead:c> [. . .] </ead:c>
            </ead:c>
         </ead:dsc>
      </eg:egXML>
   </div>
</div>
