<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xmlns:eg="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
     xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/"
     xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     xml:lang="eng"
     xml:id="elem-relation"
     type="elementDocumentation">
   <head>
      <gi>relation</gi>
      <seg type="fullName">Relation</seg>
   </head>
   <div type="summary">
      <p>A child element of <gi>relations</gi> for describing a relationship between the
                     materials described in the EAD instance and a related entity.</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>daterange, dateset, datesingle, descriptivenote, objectxmlwrap, geogname, relationentry</p>
   </div>
   <div type="mayOccurWithin">
      <p>relations</p>
   </div>
   <div type="attributes">
      <table>
         <row>
            <cell>actuate</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: none, onload, onrequest, other)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>altrender</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>arcrole</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>audience</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>encodinganalog</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>href</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>id</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>lang</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>lastdatetimeverified</cell>
            <cell>Optional (must follow pattern based on ISO 8601)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>linkrole</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>linktitle</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>otherrelationtype</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>relationtype</cell>
            <cell>Required (values limited to: cpfrelation, functionrelation, resourcerelation, otherrelationtype)</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>script</cell>
            <cell>Optional</cell>
         </row>
         <row>
            <cell>show</cell>
            <cell>Optional (values limited to: embed, new, none, other, replace)</cell>
         </row>
      </table>
   </div>
   <div type="descriptionAndUsage">
      <p>
         <gi>relation</gi> records descriptive information about a relationship between
                     the materials being described and a related entity, such as: an archival,
                     bibliographic, or other resource; a corporate body, person, or family; a
                     function; or any other entity.</p>
      <p>Use <gi>relationentry</gi> to provide a textual description of the related
                     entity. Use <gi>objectxmlwrap</gi> to embed XML documenting the related entity
                     from any namespace other than EAD3. Use <gi>date</gi>, <gi>daterange</gi>, or
                        <gi>dateset</gi> for specifying the time period of the relationship and
                        <gi>geogname</gi> for relevant location information.
                        <gi>descriptivenote</gi> may be included for more detailed specifications or
                     explanations of the relationship.</p>
      <p>The prescribed order of all child elements (both required and optional) is:</p>
      <list>
         <item>
            <gi>relationentry</gi>
         </item>
         <item>
            <gi>objectxmlwrap</gi>
         </item>
         <item>
            <gi>datesingle</gi>, <gi>daterange</gi>, and/or <gi>dateset</gi>
         </item>
         <item>
            <gi>geogname</gi>
         </item>
         <item>
            <gi>descriptivenote</gi>
         </item>
      </list>
      <p>Attribute usage:</p>
      <list>
         <item>Use <att>relationtype</att> to specify the kind of relationship being
                        encoded.</item>
         <item>Use <att>otherrelationtype</att> to specify the alternate type of
                        relationship, when <att>relationtype</att> is set to
                        "otherrelationtype"</item>
         <item>Use <att>arcrole</att> to supply a URI that describes the nature of the
                        relationship between the materials being described and the related
                        entity.</item>
         <item>Use <att>linkrole</att> to supply a URI that describes the nature of the
                        remote resource.</item>
      </list>
      <p>See also:</p>
      <list>
         <item>The children of <gi>controlaccess</gi>, which can be used to specify the
                        individuals, organizations, families, topics, and functions related to the
                        materials being described using controlled vocabularies.</item>
      </list>
      <p>Element status:</p>
      <list>
         <item>In EAD3 <gi>relation</gi> is designated an "experimental" element. This
                        status reflects a lack of consensus within the Technical Subcommittee for
                        Encoded Archival Description (TS-EAD) regarding its inclusion in the schema
                        due to concerns that it might duplicate functionality already present and a
                        lack of clarity at the time of developing EAD3 as to how Linked Data will be
                        integrated into archival description.</item>
         <item>As an "experimental" element, it is not guaranteed that
                           <gi>relations</gi> will persist in the next version of EAD in its current
                        form. However, TS-EAD encourages its use so that the EAD community will
                        learn more about how the <gi>relations</gi> model works within archival
                        description, and anticipates providing a forward migration path.</item>
      </list>
   </div>
   <div type="availability">
      <p>Required, repeatable</p>
      <p>Experimental in EAD3</p>
   </div>
   <div type="examples">
      <p>See examples under <gi>relations</gi>.</p>
   </div>
</div>
