<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
  <control><recordid>mc00212</recordid><otherrecordid localtype="url">http://www.lib.ncsu.edu/findingaids/mc00212/ead</otherrecordid><representation href="http://www.lib.ncsu.edu/findingaids/mc00212" localtype="html">Collection guide</representation><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Future Farmers of America Scrapbooks</titleproper></titlestmt><notestmt><controlnote><p>EAD generated by NCSU Libraries' Collection Guides application using data imported from ArchivesSpace.</p></controlnote></notestmt></filedesc><maintenancestatus value="new">new</maintenancestatus><maintenanceagency><agencycode>us-ncrhsus</agencycode><agencyname>North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center</agencyname></maintenanceagency><languagedeclaration><language langcode="eng">English</language><script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script></languagedeclaration><maintenancehistory><maintenanceevent><eventtype value="created"/><eventdatetime standarddatetime="2014-11-10T16:23:39-05:00"/><agenttype value="machine"/><agent>NCSU Collection Guides Application</agent></maintenanceevent></maintenancehistory></control>
  <archdesc level="collection"><did><origination><corpname source="local" rules="dacs"><part localtype="primaryPart">Future Farmers of America</part><part localtype="secondaryPart">Coats Chapter</part></corpname></origination><unittitle>Future Farmers of America Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate>1959-1962</unitdate><unitdatestructured><daterange><fromdate>1959</fromdate><todate>1962</todate></daterange></unitdatestructured><unitid>MC 00212</unitid><abstract>This collection includes two scrapbooks that contain photographs, newspaper clippings and letters from the Future Farmers of America Coats Chapter, Coats High School, Coats, North Carolina, documenting the organization from 1959 to 1962. The scrapbooks were created during the time when Murry O. Phillips taught vocational agriculture at Coats High School and contain letters to Phillips from business and civic leaders and from his state department of public instruction supervisors as well as other items documenting Phillips's life and career, especially his work with the Future Farmers of America organization. 
</abstract><abstract>Future Farmers of America, later known as the National FFA Organization, was founded in 1928. The organization brings together students, teachers and agribusiness to solidify support for agricultural education in middle and high schools where members are engaged in a wide range of curriculum and FFA activities leading to career opportunities in agriculture. There was an active chapter of Future Farmers of America in at Coats High School in Harnett County, North Carolina, during the time when Murry O. Phillips taught vocational agriculture there.</abstract><physdescstructured physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied" coverage="whole"><quantity>3</quantity><unittype>linear feet</unittype></physdescstructured><physloc>For current information on the location of these materials, please consult the Special Collections Research Center Reference Staff.</physloc><repository><corpname><part>North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center</part></corpname></repository></did><acqinfo><p>Source unknown (Accession no. 2010.0014)</p></acqinfo><arrangement><p>This collection has not yet undergone full archival processing; materials are arranged in order received.</p></arrangement><bioghist><p>Future Farmers of America, later known as the National FFA Organization, was founded in 1928. The organization brings together students, teachers and agribusiness to solidify support for agricultural education in middle and high schools where members are engaged in a wide range of curriculum and FFA activities leading to career opportunities in agriculture.</p><p>The letters FFA stand for Future Farmers of America; however, in 1988 the official name of the organization was changed from Future Farmers of America to National FFA Organization to reflect the growing diversity of agriculture, including future farmers, biologists, chemists, veterinarians, engineers and entrepreneurs.</p><p>FFA is structured on three levels: local, state and national. At the national level, FFA is led by a board of directors and six student national officers. The programs are funded through sponsorships and private donations at the local, state and national level. National dues for each member are $5 per year. </p><p>The National FFA Convention is held each October where members participate in general sessions, competitive events, educational tours, leadership workshops, a career show and expo, volunteer activities and much more. </p><p>There was an active chapter of Future Farmers of America in at Coats High School in Harnett County, North Carolina, during the time when Murry O. Phillips taught vocational agriculture there.</p></bioghist><prefercite><p>[Identification of item], Future Farmers of America Scrapbooks, MC 00212, Special Collections Research Center, North Carolina State University Libraries, Raleigh, NC</p></prefercite><processinfo><p>Processed by Judy Allen Dodson, March 2010</p></processinfo><relatedmaterial><p>Murry O. Phillips Papers (MC 00282)</p></relatedmaterial><scopecontent><p>This collection includes two scrapbooks that contain photographs, newspaper clippings and letters from the Future Farmers of America Coats Chapter, Coats High School, Coats, North Carolina, documenting the organization from 1959 to 1962. The scrapbooks were created during the time when Murry O. Phillips taught vocational agriculture at Coats High School and contain letters to Phillips from business and civic leaders and from his state department of public instruction supervisors as well as other items documenting Phillips's life and career, especially his work with the Future Farmers of America organization.</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>This collection may contain materials with sensitive or confidential information that is protected under federal or state right to privacy laws and regulations. Researchers are advised that the disclosure of certain information pertaining to identifiable living individuals represented in this collection without the consent of those individuals may have legal ramifications (e.g., a cause of action under common law for invasion of privacy may arise if facts concerning an individual's private life are published that would be deemed highly offensive to a reasonable person) for which North Carolina State University assumes no responsibility.</p></userestrict><userestrict><p>The nature of the NCSU Libraries' Special Collections means that copyright or other information about restrictions may be difficult or even impossible to determine despite reasonable efforts. The NCSU Libraries claims only physical ownership of most Special Collections materials.</p><p>The materials from our collections are made available for use in research, teaching, and private study, pursuant to U.S. Copyright law. The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to, infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><corpname source="naf"><part>Future Farmers of America</part></corpname><corpname source="local" rules="dacs"><part localtype="primaryPart">Future Farmers of America</part><part localtype="secondaryPart">Coats Chapter</part></corpname><persname source="local" rules="aacr"><part localtype="surname">Phillips</part><part localtype="forename">M. O. </part><part localtype="fullerForm">Murry Ormand</part><part localtype="existDates">1913-2000</part></persname><corpname source="naf"><part>National FFA Organization--History.</part></corpname><subject><part localtype="geographic">Coats (N.C.)</part></subject><subject><part localtype="topical">North Carolina</part><part localtype="topical">History</part><part localtype="topical">20th century</part><part localtype="topical">Agricultural education</part></subject><subject><part localtype="topical">North Carolina</part><part localtype="topical">High school students</part></subject><subject><part localtype="topical">North Carolina</part><part localtype="topical">Farmers</part></subject><subject><part localtype="topical">North Carolina</part><part localtype="topical">Farm life</part></subject><subject><part localtype="topical">North Carolina</part><part localtype="topical">Farmers</part><part localtype="topical">Attitudes</part></subject></controlaccess><dsc><c><did><unittitle>Scrapbook: Coats Chapter</unittitle><unitdate>1959-1961</unitdate><unitdatestructured><daterange><fromdate>1959</fromdate><todate>1961</todate></daterange></unitdatestructured><container localtype="flatbox">1</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Scrapbook: Coats Chapter</unittitle><unitdate>1961-1962</unitdate><unitdatestructured><daterange><fromdate>1961</fromdate><todate>1962</todate></daterange></unitdatestructured><container localtype="flatbox">2</container></did></c></dsc></archdesc>
</ead>
