<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
  <control><recordid>mc00022</recordid><otherrecordid localtype="url">http://www.lib.ncsu.edu/findingaids/mc00022/ead</otherrecordid><representation href="http://www.lib.ncsu.edu/findingaids/mc00022" localtype="html">Collection guide</representation><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Daniel Harvey Hill (1859 - 1924) Papers</titleproper></titlestmt><editionstmt><edition>Revised: 2013</edition><p>Addition to collection processed and finding aid updated by: Todd Kosmerick, 2013 July. </p></editionstmt><notestmt><controlnote><p>EAD generated by NCSU Libraries' Collection Guides application using data imported from ArchivesSpace.</p></controlnote></notestmt></filedesc><maintenancestatus value="revised">revised</maintenancestatus><maintenanceagency><agencycode>us-ncrhsus</agencycode><agencyname>North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center</agencyname></maintenanceagency><languagedeclaration><language langcode="eng">English</language><script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script></languagedeclaration><maintenancehistory><maintenanceevent><eventtype value="created"/><eventdatetime standarddatetime="2014-11-10T16:22:14-05:00"/><agenttype value="machine"/><agent>NCSU Collection Guides Application</agent></maintenanceevent></maintenancehistory></control>
  <archdesc level="collection"><did><origination><persname source="naf" rules="aacr"><part localtype="surname">Hill</part><part localtype="forename">Daniel Harvey</part><part localtype="existDates">1859-1924</part></persname></origination><unittitle>Daniel Harvey Hill (1859 - 1924) Papers</unittitle><unitdate>1883-1955</unitdate><unitdatestructured><daterange><fromdate>1883</fromdate><todate>1955</todate></daterange></unitdatestructured><unitid>MC 00022</unitid><abstract>The Daniel Harvey Hill (1859 - 1924) Papers, 1883 - 1955, contain items relating to Hill's career at North Carolina College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts (later North Carolina State University) as an English professor, Vice President, and President. Many of the materials document Hill's professional career, particularly his appointment to and resignation from the presidency of the College. There are also manuscript drafts of texts Hill wrote on the Civil War and on his father, General D. H. Hill.  A small number of personal materials are also included.  The bulk of the materials date from 1908 to early 1920s.</abstract><abstract>Daniel Harvey Hill (1859-1924) was an educator, college president, writer, and historian. He received a B.A., M.A. and Doctor of Literature degree from Davidson College. In 1908 he became the third president of the North Carolina College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts, where he served from 1908 to 1916.</abstract><physdescstructured physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied" coverage="whole"><quantity>1.25</quantity><unittype>linear feet</unittype></physdescstructured><physloc>For current information on the location of these materials, please consult the Special Collections Research Center Reference Staff.</physloc><repository><corpname><part>North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center</part></corpname></repository></did><acqinfo><p>Gift of Randolph Isabel Hill, Accessions 1967.0006, 1969.0009, and 1970.0002 (1967-1970).  Additional gifts made by North Carolina State University Office of Foundations and Development, Accession 1984.0003 (1984) and by Randye Finigan and Wendy Lawton, Accession 2013.0193 (2013).</p></acqinfo><arrangement><p>The collection is organized into two principal series:The Personal Materials series is divided between correspondence and biography.The Professional Materials series contains three subseries, namely Correspondence, Collected Newspaper Articles, and Writings.</p></arrangement><bioghist><p>Daniel Harvey Hill, the second son of Confederate general Daniel Harvey Hill and Isabella Morrison, was born at Davidson, North Carolina, on 1859 January 15. In 1880, Hill graduated from Davidson College with a Bachelor of Arts degree; shortly thereafter, he began teaching as a professor of English at the Military and Agricultural College at Milledgeville, Georgia. During the nine years he taught at that institution, Hill married Pauline White of Milledgeville (1885) and received a Master of Arts degree from Davidson College (1886). He received a Doctor of Literature from Davidson in 1905 and a Doctor of Laws from the University of North Carolina in 1910.</p><p>Hill returned to North Carolina in 1889 when he was hired at the recently-established College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts (now North Carolina State University). For almost twenty years, he served as professor of English and bookkeeping, faculty secretary, and treasurer. In 1905 he was elected Vice-President, a position he fulfilled while remaining professor of English. Three years later, Hill became the third president of the College. He held that position for eight years, resigning in 1916 to write a history of North Carolina troops during the Civil War entitled Bethel to Sharpsburg (1926). </p><p>Hill's lengthy academic career was coupled with an equally extensive literary career. His interest in North Carolina history manifested itself in his book about the state in the Civil War for the twelve-volume Confederate Military History (1899). Collaborating with colleagues, he wrote the textbooks Young People's History of North Carolina (1907) and Agriculture for Beginners (1903); a series of five schoolbooks collectively known as Hill Readers (1906); and Corn Book for Young Folk (1920). Throughout the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, Hill served as editor of The Southern Home, a weekly newspaper that had been founded by his father.</p><p>Hill participated in numerous organizations, mostly those with a historical or literary focus, during his time at the College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts. He was a member of the North Carolina Historical Commission, the North Carolina Society of the Sons of the Revolution, United Sons of Confederate Veterans, and the Southern Educational Association. He was the president of the North Carolina Teachers Assembly, the North Carolina Folklore Society, and the North Carolina Literary and Historical Association. Hill also served as chairman of the state council of defense during World War I.</p><p>Following his retirement, Hill remained in Raleigh until poor health compelled him to relocate to the western mountains of the state. He died on 1924 July 31 at Blowing Rock, North Carolina, and was survived by his wife and five children.</p></bioghist><prefercite><p>[Identification of item], Daniel Harvey Hill (1859 - 1924) Papers, 1883-1955, MC 22, Special Collections Research Center, North Carolina State University Libraries, Raleigh, NC</p></prefercite><processinfo><p>Processed by: Caitlin Donnelly, 2005; machine-readable finding aid created by: Caitlin Donnelly, 2005.  Addition to collection processed and finding aid updated by: Todd Kosmerick, 2013 July.</p></processinfo><relatedmaterial><list><item>Daniel Harvey Hill (1859 - 1924) Papers, P. C. 94, North Carolina State Archives, Raleigh</item><item>Daniel Harvey Hill (1821 - 1889) Papers (2035), Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</item><item>Daniel Harvey Hill (1821 - 1889) Diary (882), Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</item><item>Daniel Harvey Hill (1821 - 1889) Papers, North Carolina State Archives, Raleigh</item></list></relatedmaterial><scopecontent><p>This collection contains material relating to Daniel Harvey Hill and his career at North Carolina College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts, where he held positions as English professor (1889-1908), Vice-President (1905-1908), and President (1908-1916). The collection contains personal correspondence, copies of a short pamphlet written by Hill on North Carolina history, and newspaper articles about Hill, his career, and the College more generally.  Many of the materials document Hill's professional career, particularly his appointment to and resignation from the presidency of the College. There are also manuscript drafts of texts Hill wrote on the Civil War and on his father, General D. H. Hill.  A small number of personal materials are also included.  The bulk of the materials date from 1908 to early 1920s.</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>The nature of the NCSU Libraries' Special Collections means that copyright or other information about restrictions may be difficult or even impossible to determine despite reasonable efforts. The NCSU Libraries claims only physical ownership of most Special Collections materials.</p><p>The materials from our collections are made available for use in research, teaching, and private study, pursuant to U.S. Copyright law. The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to, infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><persname source="naf" rules="aacr"><part localtype="surname">Hill</part><part localtype="forename">D. H.</part><part localtype="fullerForm">Daniel Harvey</part><part localtype="existDates">1821-1889</part></persname><corpname source="naf" rules="aacr"><part>North Carolina College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts--History</part></corpname><persname source="naf" rules="aacr"><part localtype="surname">Hill</part><part localtype="forename">Daniel Harvey</part><part localtype="existDates">1859-1924</part></persname><corpname source="naf" rules="aacr"><part>North Carolina State University--History</part></corpname><persname source="naf" rules="aacr"><part localtype="surname">Hill</part><part localtype="forename">Daniel Harvey</part><part localtype="existDates">1859-1924</part></persname><subject><part localtype="topical">North Carolina</part><part localtype="topical">Historians</part></subject><subject><part localtype="genre_form">Clippings</part></subject><subject><part localtype="genre_form">Letters (correspondence)</part></subject><subject><part localtype="geographic">History</part><part localtype="geographic">North Carolina</part><part localtype="geographic">1865-</part></subject><subject><part localtype="topical">North Carolina</part><part localtype="topical">College presidents</part></subject><subject><part localtype="geographic">History</part><part localtype="geographic">North Carolina</part><part localtype="geographic">Civil War, 1861-1865</part></subject></controlaccess><dsc><c><did><unittitle>Personal Materials</unittitle><unitdate>1883 - 1920</unitdate><unitdatestructured><daterange><fromdate>1883</fromdate><todate>1920</todate></daterange></unitdatestructured></did><scopecontent><p>This series contains two letters from Daniel Harvey Hill (probably the father, Confederate Lieutenant General Daniel Harvey Hill), one to Nannie Hill and a second to Joseph Hill. The folder includes typed transcriptions of both letters. Also included in this series is an undated biography of the father.  Finally, the series has three portrait photographs of Daniel Harvey Hill (the son).</p></scopecontent><c><did><unittitle>Letters</unittitle><unitdate>1883, 1916</unitdate><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">1</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>"Lt. Gen. Daniel Harvey Hill: Senior Soldier,"</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920</unitdate><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">2</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate>Circa 1900</unitdate><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">1</container></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Professional Materials</unittitle><unitdate>1901 - 1955</unitdate><unitdatestructured><daterange><fromdate>1901</fromdate><todate>1955</todate></daterange></unitdatestructured></did><scopecontent><p>The Professional Materials series is divided into three subseries. The Correspondence subseries includes letters and telegrams Hill received in honor of his appointment to and resignation from the presidency at the North Carolina College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts. The Collected Newspaper Articles and Addresses includes materials about Hill's career, specifically his resignation in 1916, as well as newspaper articles about the College's search in 1916 for a president, general College news from a 1924 Raleigh News and Observer, the 1955 dedication of D. H. Hill Library at North Carolina State College of Agriculture and Engineering (later North Carolina State University), and an undated [circa 1920] editorial. Also included are materials on General D. H. Hill and an ancestor named William Hill.  The Writing subseries includes a pamphlet on North Carolina history published by Hill as well as his resignation letter to the Board of Trustees and former students of North Carolina College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts.  There are also manuscript drafts of texts Hill wrote on the Civil War and on his father, the general.</p></scopecontent><c><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1894 - 1916</unitdate></did><c><did><unittitle>1894 April 16</unittitle><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">2</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>1908 July 23 - July 25</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">3</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>1908 July 26 - September 29</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">4</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>1915 December 31 - 1916 February 15</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">5</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>1916 April 10 - May 22</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">6</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>1916 May 23 - August 2</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">7</container></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Collected Newspaper Articles and Addresses</unittitle><unitdate>1916 - 1955, undated</unitdate></did><c><did><unittitle>Archer Anderson Address on General Daniel Harvey Hill</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">3</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Daniel Harvey Hill</unittitle><unitdate>1916 - 1920</unitdate><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">8</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>North Carolina College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts</unittitle><unitdate>1916 - 1955</unitdate><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">9</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>William Hill Narrative of the 1770 Campaign in South Carolina under Thomas Sumter</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">4</container></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Writings</unittitle><unitdate>1901 - Circa 1920</unitdate></did><c><did><unittitle>Life of General D. H. Hill (Handwritten Draft) (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate>1915</unitdate><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">5</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Life of General D. H. Hill (Handwritten Draft) (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate>1915</unitdate><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">6</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Life of General D. H. Hill (Typed Draft) (1 of 2)</unittitle><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">7</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Life of General D. H. Hill (Typed Draft) (2 of 2)</unittitle><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">8</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>"The North Carolina Booklet: Greene's Retreat,"</unittitle><unitdate>1901</unitdate><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">10</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>North Carolina in the Civil War, copy 1 (Typed Draft) (1 of 3)</unittitle><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">9</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>North Carolina in the Civil War, copy 1 (Typed Draft) (2 of 3)</unittitle><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">10</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>North Carolina in the Civil War, copy 1 (Typed Draft) (3 of 3)</unittitle><container localtype="legalbox">2</container><container localtype="folder">11</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>North Carolina in the Civil War, copy 2 (Typed Draft) (1 of 3)</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">3</container><container localtype="folder">1</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>North Carolina in the Civil War, copy 2 (Typed Draft) (1 of 3)</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">3</container><container localtype="folder">2</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>North Carolina in the Civil War, copy 2 (Typed Draft) (3 of 3)</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">3</container><container localtype="folder">3</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Pages Possibly from a Draft of the Life of General D. H. Hill</unittitle><container localtype="halfbox">3</container><container localtype="folder">4</container></did></c><c><did><unittitle>Resignation Letters</unittitle><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container localtype="halfbox">1</container><container localtype="folder">11</container></did></c></c></c></dsc></archdesc>
</ead>
